Finding Aid for Jeffrey R. Parsons papers, 1960-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Archaeological Sites and Projects 1966-2010
  - Peru 1996-2010
    - Wanka Survey
      - Jau-EI-49(P) 4438 B NE Jauja 1976 Coll 205P 544 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-50(P) 4438 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 206P 493 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-51(P) 4760 A NE Jauja 1976 Coll 209P, 210P (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-52(P) 4760 D SW Jauja 1976 Coll 211P 487 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-53(P) 4754 A SE Jauja 1976 Fea 15P 534 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-54(P) 4282 C SW Jauja 1976 Coll 219P 583 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-55(P) 4280 C SW Jauja 1976 Coll 222P 484 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-56(P) 4280 A SE Jauja 1976 Coll 227P 619 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-57(P) 4280 D SE Jauja 1976 Coll 231P 624 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-58(P) 4280 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 232P 589 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-59(P) 4280 B SW Jauja 1976 Coll 246P 620 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-60(P) 4638 D SW Jauja 1976 Coll 252P 636 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-61(P) 4272 D NE Jauja 1976 Coll 258P 384 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-62(P) 4742 D NE Jauja 1976 Coll 259P 383 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-63(P) 4418 C NW Jauja 1976 Coll 266P 417 See Jau-EI-3(H) (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-64(P) 4300 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 273P, 274P 463 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-65(P) 4416 A SW Jauja 1976 Coll 278P, 279P 280P 446 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-66(P) 38 61 52 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 281P 447 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-67(P) 38 61 52 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 285P 450 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-68(P) 4278 B SW Jauja 1976 Coll 242P 630 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-69(P) 38 61 52 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 286P 452 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-70(P) 38 61 52 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 289P 451 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-71(P) 38 61 50 SE Jauja 1976 Coll 293P 453 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-72(P) 38 61 50 SE Jauja 1976 Coll 296P 455 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-73(P) 38 61 50 NW Jauja 1976 Coll 297P 457 (Box 54)
      - Jau-EI-74(P) 38 61 50 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 298P 456 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-1(P) 4422 D NW Jauja 1975 Coll 53P 388 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-2(P) 4316 A SW Jauja 1975 Unit 69P 426 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-3(P) 4422 D SW Jauja 1975 Coll 55P 389 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-4(P) 4424 A SE Jauja 1975 Coll 56P 395 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-5(P) 4424 A SE Jauja 1975 Coll 57P 394 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-6(P) 4424 D NW Jauja 1975 Coll 58P 396 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-7(P) 4422 D NE Jauja 1975 Coll 60P 387 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-8(P) 4316 B SE 4294 D SE/NE Jauja 1975 Unit 63P Coll 61-64P 431 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-9(P) 4316 B NW Jauja 1975 Unit 67P 427 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-10(P) 4316 A NE Jauja 1975 Unit 68P 425 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-11(P) 4294 A NW Jauja 1975 Coll 80P 591 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-12(P) 4294 NW Jauja 1975 Unit 74P 590 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-13(P) 4654 D NW Jauja 1975 Unit 73P 601 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-14(P) 4292 B NE Jauja 1975 Unit 72P 611 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-15(P) 4656 C NE/SE 4656 D NW Jauja 1976 Unit 75P, 76P Coll 90-99P 472 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-16(P) 4656 A SW Jauja 1975 Unit 77P 596 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-17(P) 4656 B NE Jauja 1975 Coll 105P 597 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-18(P) 4290 B NW Jauja 1975 Unit 86P Col 121, 122P 556 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-19(P) 4290 B SE Jauja 1975 Unit 88P 558 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-20(P) 4286 C SW Jauja 1975 Unit 90P Coll 125P, 126P 565 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-21(P) 4286 D NW Unit 91P 566 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-22(P) 4286 D NE Jauja 1975 Unit 93P 567 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-23(P) 4286 D NE Jauja 1975 Coll 133P 568 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-24(P) 4428 C SW Jauja 1975 Coll 144P 501 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-25(P) 4428 C SW Jauja 1975 Coll 145P, 146P 499 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-26(P) 4430 C SW Jauja 1975 Coll 150P 505 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-27(P) Jauja 1975 See Jau-LH-10(P) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-28(P) Jauja 1975 See Jau-LH-16(P) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-29(P) 4752 A NE Jauja 1976 Coll 157P 513 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-30(P) 4752 A SE Jauja 1976 Coll 158P 532 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-31(P) 4752 A NE Jauja 1976 Coll 159P 514 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-32(P) 4752 A NE Jauja 1976 Coll 160P, 161P 515 (Box 54)
      - Jau-Li-33(P) 4987 C NW/SW Jauja 1976 Unit 104P Coll 191P -- 197P "Tunanmarca" 468 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-34(P) 4438 D SW Jauja 1976 Coll 190P, 198P, 199P 490 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-35(P) 4760 C NW Jauja 1976 Coll 207P 482 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-36(P) 4760 C NW Jauja 1976 Coll 208P 483 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-37(P) 4282 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 213P -- 215P 579 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-38(P) 4282 D SW Jauja 1976 Coll 216P, 217P 587 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-39(P) 4282 B SW Jauja 1976 Coll 218P 575 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-40(P) 4282 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 220P 572 See Jau-LI-14(H) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-41(P) 4282 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 221P 574 See Jau-LI-12(H) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-42(P) 4282 D SW Jauja 1976 no collection 584 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-43(P) 4280 B NE Jauja 1976 Coll 224P, 225P, 226P 618 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-44(P) 4280 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 228P, 229P 621 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-45(P) 4280 D SW Jauja 1976 Coll 230P 625 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-46(P) 4278 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 234P 626 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-47(P) 4278 D SW Jauja 1976 Coll 235P, 236P 627 (Box 54)
      - Jau-Li-48(P) 4278 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 241P 629 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-49(P) 4278 B SW Jauja 1976 Coll 243P 631 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-50(P) 4278 B SW Jauja 1976 Coll 244P, 245P 632 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-51(P) 4638 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 247P -- 249P Unit 109P 634 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-52(P) 4638 C NE Jauja 1976 Coll 250P, 251P Unit 110P 635 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-53(P) 4638 D SE Jauja 1976 Coll 253P 633 "Lupuc" (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-54(P) 4746 C SW Jauja 1976 Coll 254P 399 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-55(P) 4748 B NE Jauja 1976 Coll 256P, 257P 503 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-56(P) 4744 D NE Jauja 1976 Coll 260P 393 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-57(P) 4742 C NE Jauja 1976 Coll 263P 385 also Jau-LH-28(P) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-58(P) 4418 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 264P 416 See Jau-LI-2(H) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-59(P) 4734 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 268P 408 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-60(P) 4416 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 270P 415 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-61(P) 4300 B NE Jauja 1976 Coll 275P, 276P 465 See Jau-LI-4(H) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-62(P) 38 61 52 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 283P, 284P 449 "Ushnu" (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-63(P) 38 61 295 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 11P 406 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-64(P) 38 61 295 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 112P 401 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-65(P) 38 61 295 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 113P ? (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-66(P) 38 61 295 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 114P 403 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-67(P) 38 61 295 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 115P 402 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-68(P) 38 61 295 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 116P 405 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-69(P) 38 61 295 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 117P 407 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-70(P) 4302 D NE Jauja 1976 Unit 121P 461 "Chawin" (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-71(P) 4302 A SW 4302 B NW Jauja 1976 Coll 291P, 292P 462 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-72(P) 38 61 50 SE Jauja 1976 Coll 294P, 295P 454 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-73(P) 38 61 50, 4302 C, 4302 D, 4987 D, 4987 A, Fea 24P -- 33P 459 Canal, Aqueduct, Reservoir (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-74(P) 38 61 50 NW, 38 61 125 NE Jauja 1976 Fea 28P, 29P 459A (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-75(P) 4987 B, 4987 D Jauja 1976 Fea 34P 468A (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-76(P) 38 61 125 NE Jauja 1976 Unit 122P 479 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-77(P) 38 61 123 SE Jauja 1976 Unit 123P 481 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI78(P) 38 61 123 SW Jauja 1976 Unit 124P 480 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LI-79(P) 38 61 125 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 299P 478 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-1(P) 4316 B SW Jauja 1975 Unit 64P 606 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-2(P) 4316 B NW Jauja 1975 Unit 65P 428 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-3(P) 4292 D SW Jauja 1975 Unit 78P 613 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-4(P) 4292 D SW Jauja 1975 Unit 79P 611 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-5(P) 4292 D SW Jauja 1975 Unit 80P 612 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-6(P) 4290 C SW 4290 D NW Jauja 1975 Unit 81P 548 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-7(P) 4290 D SW Jauja 1975 Unit 82P Coll 112-116P Fea 13P Coll 80H 550 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-8(P) 4290 C SW Jauja 1975 Unit 83P 547 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-9(P) 4290 C SW Jauja 1975 Unit 84P 546 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-10(P) 4290 D NW Jauja 1975 Unit 85P 554 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-11(P) 4290 A SE Jauja 1975 Unit 87P 555 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-12(P) 4290 B NE Jauja 1975 Unit 89P 568 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-13(P) 4286 D NW Jauja 1975 Unit 92P 566 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-14(P) 4428 D SW Jauja 1975 Unit 95P 502 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-15(P) 4428 C SW Jauja 1975 Unit 96P 500 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-16(P) 4428 D SW Jauja 1975 Unit 97P Coll 147P, Coll 148P 504 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-17(P) 4430 B NE Jauja 1976 Coll 151P 553 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-18(P) 4432 C SW Jauja 1976 Unit 98P Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-19(P) 4752 A NE Jauja 1976 Unit 99P 514 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-20(P) 4752 A NE Jauja 1976 Unit 100P 516 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-21(P) 4752 A SE Jauja 1976 517 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-22(P) 4754 A SW Jauja 1976 Coll 170P See Jau-?-7(P) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-23(P) 4754 D NW Jauja 1976 Unit 102P 528 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-24(P) 4434 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 180P 539 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-25(P) 4438 B NW Jauja 1976 Unit 103P 491 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-26(P) 4438 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 189P 492 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-27(P) 4760 C SW Jauja 1976 Unit 106P 485 Colcas (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-28(P) 4742 C NE Jauja 1976 Coll 263P 385 See Jau-LI-57(P) (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-29(P) 4282 B NE Jauja 1976 Unit 107P 580 (Box 54)
      - Jau-LH-30(P) 38 61 125 SE Jauja 1976 Fea 36P 458 Inca highway (Box 54)
      - Jau-Col-1(P) 4316 B SW Jauja 1975 Unit 66P 429 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-1(P) 4422 C SE Jauja 1975 Coll 52P 386 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-2(P) 4424 C SE Jauja 1975 Coll 140P 390 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-3(P) 4428 B SW Jauja 1975 Coll 143P 552 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-4(P) 4428 B SW Jauja 1975 Coll 134P 570 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-5(P) 4290 D NW Jauja 1975 Coll 120P 549 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?6(P) 4752 B SW Jauja 1976 Coll 166P 523 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-7(P) 4754 A NW Jauja 1976 Coll 169-P, 170P 525 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-8(P) 4754 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 173P 535 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-9(P) 4436 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 183P 540 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-10(P) 4436 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 184P 537 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-11(P) 4436 D NE Jauja 1976 Coll 185P 536 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-12(P) 4436 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 186P 538 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-13(P) 4754 D SE Jauja 1976 Fea 16P 496 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-14(P) 4438 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 203P 494 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-15(P) 4760 C SE Jauja 1976 Unit 105P 486 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-16(P) 4760 B SE Jauja 1976 Fea 17-P 615 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-17(P) 4440 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 212P 614 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-18(P) 4760 B SW Jauja 1976 Coll 223P 616 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-19(P) 4278 D SE Jauja 1976 Coll 233P 617 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-20(P) 4278 A SE Jauja 1976 Coll 238P 622 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-21(P) 4278 A SW Jauja 1976 Coll 239P 632A (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-22(P) 4278 B SE Jauja 1976 Coll 240P 628 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-23(P) 4744 D NE Jauja 1976 Coll 261P 400 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-24(P) 4744 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 262P 392 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-25(P) 4418 D NW Jauja 1976 Coll 265P 418 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-26(P) 4734 C NW Jauja 1976 Coll 267P 410 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-27(P) 4734 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 269P 409 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-28(P) 4416 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 271P 414 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-29(P) 4414 C SE, 4414 D NE Jauja 1976 Coll 272P 411 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-30(P) 4300 A SW Jauja 1976 Coll 277P 466 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-31(P) 38 61 52 NE Jauja 1976 Coll 282P 448 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-32(P) 4282 D SE Jauja 1976 Unit 108P 582 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-33(P) 4418 A NE Jauja 1976 Unit 118P 421 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-34(P) 4418 A NE Jauja 1976 Unit 119P 422 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-35(P) 4414 C SE Jauja 1976 Unit 120P 412 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-36(P) 4282 B NE Jauja 1976 Fea 18P 585 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-37(P) 4282 B SE Jauja 1976 Fea 19P 586 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-38(P) East of 4474 above Yauli, an 1:25000 Jauja 1976 Fea 20P 382 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-39(P) 4414 C SE Jauja 1976 Fea 21P 413 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-40(P) 4300 A SW Jauja 1976 Fea 22P 467 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-41(P) 4282 A SW Jauja 1976 Fea 23P 581 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-42(P) 4302 C SE Jauja 1976 Coll 290P 460 (Box 54)
      - Jau-?-43(P) 4987 A SW Jauja 1976 Fea 35P 475 (Box 54)
      - Jauja, Peru Map (Box 54)
    - Field Notebooks
      Field Notebooks are also included and correspond to research in Junin, Wanka, and other regions in the Upper Mantaro. These are rich in data and document daily survey work. Data in these was gathered by Julia Medel, Clorinda Costi, Phil Tugendrajch, Charles Hastings, David Wilson, Daniel Morales, Ramiro Matos, David Wilson, Chris Rudecoff, Reuben García, Kurt Anchuetz, Paul Liffman, Juan Ramirez,and Parsons himself.
      - Parson-Andean Trip #1, 2 & 3 1966, 3 volumes (Box 52)
      - Parsons-#1 Tarma 1975 #2 Peru 1975 #3 Jauja 1975, 3 volumes (Box 52)
      - David Wilson #1 & Charles Hastings 1975 Hastings #2 Tarma & Jauja 1975, 2 volumes (Box 52)
      - Parsons -- #1 & 4 Jauja 1965 #2 Junin & Jauja 1976 #3 Junin 1976, 3 volumes (Box 52)
      - Parsons -- Junin 1976 Alternate notebook; Peru 1975/76 Records, 2 volumes (Box 52)
      - Tugendrajch-Anschuetz-#1 Casaracra 1976 Junin 1976 Book2; Hastings Huasahuasi 1976, 3 volumes (Box 52)
      - Lima Labwork-Artifact Inventory #1, 2, 3 2004 (Box 52)
- Topical Files 1967-1991
  The Topical Files, 1967-1991 (0 .75 linear feet) series contains files on permits, proposals, grants, expense reports, and other correspondence regarding Parsons' field projects, as well as the Otomi project with the National Geographic Society.
  - Texcoco Project 1967, 1967-1968 (Box 24)
  - Chalco Informe (INAH) 1969, 1969-1971 (Box 24)
  - Chalco Survey 1969 (Box 24)
  - Ixtapalapa 1969, 1968-1969 (Box 24)
  - Mexico 1972 Student Interviews, 1971-1972 (Box 24)
  - Mexico 1973 (Box 24)
  - Permit Letters for Mexican Survey 1971-1973 (Box 24)
  - Peruvian Project 1974, 1975-1979 (Box 24)
  - Chalco-Xochimilco Publication 1979-1980 (Box 24)
  - Mexico 1980, 1979-1982 (Box 24)
  - Peru 1980 Hastings, Charles, 1979-1981 (Box 24)
  - Peru Miscellaneous Matters 1982 (Box 24)
  - Peru Vehicle 1982 (Box 24)
  - Analysis Grant 1983, 1983-1986 (Box 24)
  - Otomi-National Geographic Society 1984 (Box 24)
  - Otomi-Wenner Gren 1984 (Box 24)
  - Otomi-Maguey Project 1985 Proposal, 1985, 1985-1991 (Box 24)
  - Salt Making Study-National Geographic Society proposal 1987, 1987-1989 (Box 24)
  - Iceland 1986, 1 volumes (Box 24)
- Publications
  The Publications, 1971-2013 (0.5 linear feet) series is made up mostly of monographs published by the Museum of Anthropology of the University of Michigan and the Pennsylvania State University's Department of Anthropology. Parsons is the author or collaborator for the listed publications. These document his work on systematic settlement pattern surveys, ethnographic research, and ceramic surveys in Mexico and Peru.
  - Prehistoric Settlement Patterns in the Texcoco Region, Mexico, (Memoirs of the Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Number 3), Jeffrey R. Parsons 1971 (Box 24)
  - Prehispanic Settlement Patterns of the Ixtapalapa Peninsula Region, Mexico, (Occasional Papers in Anthropology, The Pennsylvania State University, Number 6), Richard Edward Blanton 1972 (Box 24)
  - Prehispanic Settlement Patterns in the Southern Valley of Mexico, The Chalco-Xochimilco region, (Memoirs of the Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Number 14), Jeffrey R. Parsons et al. 1982 (Box 25)
  - Archaeological Settlement pattern Data from the Chalco, Xochimilco, Ixtapalapa, Texcoco and Zumpango Regions, Mexico, (Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Techincal Reports, Number 14, Research Reports in Archaeology, Contribution 9), Jeffrey R. Parsons et al. 1983 (Box 25)
  - Prehispanic Settlement Patterns in the Northwestern Valley of Mexico, The Zumpango Region, (Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Memoirs Number 45), Jeffrey R. Parsons 2008 (Box 25)
  - Prehispanic Settlement Patterns in the Upper Mantaro and Tarma Drainages, Junín, Peru, The Taram-Chinchaycocha Region, (Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Memoirs Number 34), Jeffrey R. Parsons et al. 2000, 2 volumes (Box 25)
  - Prehispanic Settlement Patterns in the Upper Mantaro, Junín, Peru, The Wanka Region, (Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Memoirs Number 53), Jeffrey R. Parsons et al. 2013 vol.2 (Box 25)
  - Maguey Utilization in Highland Central Mexico An archaeological Ethnography (Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Anthropological Papers No.82), Jeffrey R. Parsons 1990 (Box 25)
  - The Last Saltmakers of Nexquipayac, Mexico An archaeological Ethnography (Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Anthropological Papers No.92), Jeffrey R. Parsons 2001 (Box 25)
  - The Last Pescadores of Chimalhuacán, Mexico An archaeological Ethnography (Museum of Anthropology, University of Michigan, Anthropological Papers No.96), Jeffrey R. Parsons 2006 (Box 25)
  - Ancient Mesoamerica article 1996 (Box 25)
  - Archaeology of Drylands -- Illustrations & Photos 2001 (Box 25)
  - Inka Paper undated (Box 25)
  - Parsons, Brumfiel & Hodge undated (Box 25)
  - Texcoco Monograph -- Uru postcards (Box 25)
- Student Years 1962-1966
  The Student Years, 1962-1966 (0.25 linear feet) series contains field notebooks from Parsons' years as a student working as a field assistant in the Teotihuacan Valley Project in Mexico and Guatemala Project, both sponsored by the Pennsylvania State University.
  The notebooks include journals, field notes and photo records by Parsons, Mary Hrones, Robert Bettarel, John Speth, Richard Blanton, and William Englebrecht. The notebooks are arranged by site and date.
  - Teotihuacan Valley 1962-1966
    - Field Notebooks (7) (Box 25)
  - Guatemala 1966
    - Field Notebook (Box 25)
- Visual Materials Series 1961-2010
  The Visual Materials Series, 1961-2010 (3.5 linear feet) is composed of photo negatives of archaeological sites in Mexico and Peru arranged by site and year. The series also includes DVDs with digital scans of these negatives as well as aerial photos & small maps of Peru. Scans of the photo negatives as well as digital photos of Peru ceramic materials are digitally accessible through links in this finding aid.
  - Photo Negatives
    - Texcoco 1967, 2 volumes
      (Rolls 1-53; Rolls 54-98)
      - Rolls 1-5 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 6-10 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 11-15 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 16-20 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 21-25 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 25-30 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 31-35 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 36-40 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 41-45 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 46-50 (Box 26)
      - Rolls 51-55
        - Rolls 51-55 (Box 26)
        - Rolls 51-55 (Box 27)
          (continued)
      - Rolls 56-60 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 61-65 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 66-70 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 71-75 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 76-80 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 81-85 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 86-90 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 91-95 (Box 27)
      - Rolls 96-98 (Box 27)
    - Mexico 1966
      - Rolls 1-25 (Box 28)
        (not digitized)
    - Mexico 1969
      - Rolls 1-5 (Box 28)
      - Rolls 6-10 (Box 28)
      - Rolls 11-16 (Box 28)
    - Mexico-Ixtapalapa 1969 (Blanton) (Box 29)
      - Rolls 1-5 (Box 29)
      - Rolls 6-10 (Box 29)
      - Rolls 11-15 (Box 29)
      - Rolls 16-20 (Box 29)
      - Rolls 21-25 (Box 29)
      - Rolls 26-30 (Box 29)
      - Rolls 31-36 (Box 29)
    - Mexico 1972, 2 volumes
      (Rolls 1-27; Rolls 28-53)
      - Rolls 1-5 (Box 30)
      - Rolls 6-10 (Box 30)
      - Rolls 11-15 (Box 30)
      - Rolls 16-20 (Box 30)
      - Rolls 21-25 (Box 30)
      - Rolls 26-30 (Box 30)
      - Rolls 31-35 (Box 31)
      - Rolls 36-40 (Box 31)
      - Rolls 41-45 (Box 31)
      - Rolls 51-53 (Box 31)
    - Zumpango 1973 (Box 32)
      - Rolls 1-5 (Box 32)
      - Rolls 6-10 (Box 32)
      - Rolls 11-15 (Box 32)
      - Rolls 16-20 (Box 32)
    - Peru-Junin Survey 1975 (Box 55)
      - Jauja 1975
        - Rolls 35-38 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 29-41 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 42-45 (Box 55)
      - Tarma 1975
        - Rolls 1-5 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 6-10 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 11-15 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 16-20 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 21-25 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 25-30 (Box 55)
        - Rolls 31-34 (Box 55)
    - Peru-Junin Survey 1976 Huasahuasi, 1976 (Box 56)
      - Huasahuasi 1976
        - Rolls 1-5 (Box 56)
        - Rolls 6-8 (Box 56)
      - Jauja 1976
        - Rolls 21-25 (Box 56)
        - Rolls 26-30 (Box 56)
        - Rolls 32-35 (Box 56)
        - Ceramics Rolls 43-47a (Box 56)
      - Junin 1976
        - Rolls 10-13 (Box 56)
        - Rolls 14-16 (Box 56)
        - Rolls 16-20 (Box 56)
        - Rolls 35-38 (Box 56)
  - DVDs
    The DVDs subseries contains the original scans (tiff files) created from the photographic negative. All of these images are available on line through links in the "Photographic negatives subseries.
    - Texcoco 1967 Rolls 1-53 (Box 25)
    - Texcoco 1967 Rolls 54-75 (Box 25)
    - Texcoco 1967 Rolls 76-98 (Box 25)
    - Mexico 1972 Rolls 1-27 (Box 25)
    - Mexico 1972 Rolls 28-53 (Box 25)
    - Mexico 1969 Zumpango 1973 (Box 25)
    - Ixtapalapa 1969 (Box 25)
  - Aerial Photos and Tracings 1962-1976, undated
    - Peru Aerial Photos & Maps
      - Site 332 Shimapunta -- Museum of Anthropology (Box 57)
      - Mantaro Valley -- airphoto 1962 (Box 57)
      - La Oroya or Jauja Airphotos 1963 (Box 57)
      - Tarma:Jauja 1975 1:60000 photos (Box 57)
      - Tarma-Jauja 1975 1:40000 Tracings also 1:60000 and 1:17500 (Box 57)
      - Jauja 1:40000 tracings 1976 (Box 57)
      - Huasa Site Blow-Up,s 1976 (Box 57)
      - Peruvian Airphot-Junin (Box 57)
      - Upper Mantaro Survey/ Small Scale Regional Map negatives and 1 blank set (Box 57)
      - Upper mantaro Survey -- Reduced Base Maps (Box 57)
      - Wanka region (Box 57)
      - Miscellaneous Maps (Box 57)
      - Photostatic Negatives of 1:100000 Upper Mantaro-Tarma Maps (Box 57)
    - Junin Aerial Photos
      - Huasahuasi 1976 (Box 58)
      - Ricran, Tapo, Tingo (Box 58)
      - Jauja 1976, 1:40000 (Box 58)
      - Tarma area (Box 58)
      - Huasahuasi Area, tambo Colorado/ Atocsayco Area? 1970 (Box 58)
      - Pachacaya Area -- between la Oroya & Jauja 1:40000 1962 (Box 58)
      - Acolla-Huaricolca 1961 (Box 58)
      - Main Mantaro Valley 1970 (Box 58)
      - Jauja 1970 (Box 59)
      - Junin 1976, Tracings (Box 59)
      - Huasa 1976, 1:20000 Photo Tracings (Box 59)
      - Junin 1976, 1:40000 photos / maps (Box 59)
      - West 1962 (Box 59)
      - East 1962 (Box 59)
      - Junin 1976 (Box 59)
      - Tarma-Tarma-Jauja 1962 (Box 59)
      - All high Puna, near Lake Junin 1962, 21443 -- 21451 30867 -- 30877 (Box 59)
      - All high Puna, near Lake Junin, 12187 -- 12211 (Box 59)
      - Casaracra, Tombo Colorado, La Oroya Area (Box 59)
      - Junin 1976 (Box 59)
  - Peru-Jauja Ceramics Digital Photos 2010
    - Images PEC00001-PEC00100
    - Images PEC00101-PEC00200
    - Images PEC00201-PEC00300
    - Images PEC00301-PEC00400
    - Images PEC00401-PEC00500
    - Images PEC00501-PEC00600
    - Images PEC00601-PEC00700
    - Images PEC00601-PEC00700
- Maps 1960-1984